[
    {
        "group_id": "TIME",
        "question": "Iré al parque el Lunes",
        "answer": "I will go to the park on Monday" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "TIME",
        "question": "Mi cumpleaños es en Febrero",
        "answer": "My birthday is in February" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "TIME",
        "question": "Me reuniré con él a la noche",
        "answer": "I will meet him at night" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "TIME",
        "question": "Esa ley no se ha modificado desde 1980",
        "answer": "That law hasn't been modified since 1980" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "TIME",
        "question": "He estado trabajando allí durante 2 años",
        "answer": "I have been working there for 2 years" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "TIME",
        "question": "Trabajamos de Lunes a Viernes",
        "answer": "We work from Monday to Friday" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "TIME",
        "question": "Él está de vacaciones hasta el Viernes",
        "answer": "He is on holiday until Friday" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "TIME",
        "question": "Estará de vuelta para las seis",
        "answer": "He will be back by six o'clock" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "TIME",
        "question": "¿A qué hora te viene bien?",
        "answer": "What time is fine for you?" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "TIME",
        "question": "Normalmente llegas a la hora recomendada",
        "answer": "You usually arrive at recommended time" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "TIME",
        "question": "Él sale de casa en el último minuto",
        "answer": "He leaves home at the last minute" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "TIME",
        "question": "¿Vendrás en Navidades?",
        "answer": "Will you come at Christmas?" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "TIME",
        "question": "##SUBJECT## abrir la tienda en ##TIME##",
        "answer": "##SUBJECT## going to open the store in ##TIME##",
        "randomize": {
            "SUBJECT": {
                "question": ["Van a", "Voy a"],
                "answer": ["They are", "I am"]
            },
            "TIME": {
                "question": ["verano", "invierno"],
                "answer": ["summer", "winter"]
            }
        }
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "Invitar a alguien a cenar",
        "answer": "Invite somebody to dinner" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "Tengo prisa",
        "answer": "I'm hurry" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "Él puso una canción",
        "answer": "He played a song" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "Tú le esperaste",
        "answer": "You waited for him" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "Mira ese coche",
        "answer": "Look at that car" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "Invitar a alguien a cenar",
        "answer": "Invite somebody to dinner" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "Conducir a lo largo de la calle principal",
        "answer": "Drive along the mail street" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "Pasar un buen rato",
        "answer": "Have a great time" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "Odio esperar por gente que llega tarde",
        "answer": "I hate waiting for people who are late" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "Nos reuniremos en un café bar",
        "answer": "We will meet in a cofee bar" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "Ellos esperaron a sus amigos",
        "answer": "They waited for their friends" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "Nosotros salimos del club muy tarde",
        "answer": "We left the club very late" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "Lo siento, pero no estoy deacuerdo contigo",
        "answer": "I'm sorry, but I don't agree with you" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "Pedí un sandwich de pollo, pero esto es atún",
        "answer": "I asked for a chicken sandwich, but this is tuna" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "Necesito hablar (talk) con Martín acerca de la reunión",
        "answer": "I have to talk to Martín about the meeting" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "Yo no gasto mucho dinero en comida",
        "answer": "I don't spend much money on food" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "No te preocupes por el test. No era difícil.",
        "answer": "Don't worry about the test. It wasn't difficult." 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "¿Crees en fantasmas?",
        "answer": "Do you believe en ghosts?" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "VERBS",
        "question": "¿A quién pertenece esta bolsa?",
        "answer": "Who does this bag belong to?" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "PLACE",
        "question": "Mis padres se estaban sentando en el sofá",
        "answer": "My parents were sitting on the sofa" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "PLACE",
        "question": "Mis padres se estaban sentando en el sofá",
        "answer": "My parents were sitting on the sofa" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "PLACE",
        "question": "Llegué a Paris la noche del Viernes",
        "answer": "I arrived in Paris on Friday night" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "PLACE",
        "question": "Estaba muy cansado cuando llegué al hotel",
        "answer": "I was very tired when I arrived at hotel" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "PLACE",
        "question": "Yo voy a pie",
        "answer": "I go on foot" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "PLACE",
        "question": "Ella va a trabajar en bicicleta",
        "answer": "She goes to work by bike" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "PLACE",
        "question": "Tú estás cerca de ella",
        "answer": "You are close to her" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "PLACE",
        "question": "Me reuniré con él en ##PLACE##",
        "answer": "I'll meet him at ##PLACE##" ,
        "randomize": {
            "PLACE": {
                "question": ["la escuela", "el aeropuerto", "casa"],
                "answer": ["school", "the airport", "home"]
            }
        } 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "PLACE",
        "question": "Él está en ##PLACE##",
        "answer": "He is in the ##PLACE##",
        "randomize": {
            "PLACE": {
                "question": ["el museo", "el parque", "el coche", "la cocina"],
                "answer": ["museum", "park", "car", "kitchen"]
            }
        } 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "PLACE",
        "question": "Puse el libro en ##PLACE##",
        "answer": "I put the book on the ##PLACE##",
        "randomize": {
            "PLACE": {
                "question": ["la mesa", "el sofá", "el césped", "el suelo"],
                "answer": ["table", "coach", "grass", "floor"]
            }
        } 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "PLACE",
        "question": "##SUBJECT## ha llegado a ##PLACE##",
        "answer": "##SUBJECT## has arrived in ##PLACE##",
        "randomize": {
            "PLACE": {
                "question": ["Madrid", "España"],
                "answer": ["Madrid", "Spain"]
            },
            "SUBJECT": {
                "question": ["Él", "Ella"],
                "answer": ["He", "She"]
            }
        } 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "PLACE",
        "question": "Tengo la foto en el teléfono",
        "answer": "I have the picture on the phone" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "OTHER",
        "question": "No esperes tener una lectura entretenida",
        "answer": "Don't expect to have an amusing reading" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "OTHER",
        "question": "Después de salir del trabajo, fuí a comer",
        "answer": "After leaving work, I went to have lunch" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "OTHER",
        "question": "Marta se despertó después que sonase el reloj",
        "answer": "Marta woke up after the clock rang" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "OTHER",
        "question": "Ella fue a un restaurante vegano a las 3",
        "answer": "She went to a veggie restaurant at three o'clock" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "OTHER",
        "question": "Él fué a dormir despues de tomase una taza de café",
        "answer": "He went to sleep after drinking a cup of cofee" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "OTHER",
        "question": "¿Cómo es ella? (Personalidad)",
        "answer": "How is she like?" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "OTHER",
        "question": "¿Cómo es ella? (Apariencia)",
        "answer": "What does she look like?" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "OTHER",
        "question": "En lo que se refiere a su personalidad, ella es muy amable",
        "answer": "As regards to her personality, She is very kind" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "OTHER",
        "question": "Tengo nariz grande",
        "answer": "I have a big nose" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "OTHER",
        "question": "Tengo ojos azules",
        "answer": "I have blue eyes" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "OTHER",
        "question": "Me encontré con él en el parque",
        "answer": "I met him in the park" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "OTHER",
        "question": "Hacía tanto frío que no podíamos ir al parque",
        "answer": "It was so cold that we couldn't go to park" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "OTHER",
        "question": "Nosotros estábamos paseando al perro",
        "answer": "We were taking the dog for a walk" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "OTHER",
        "question": "Fuí a dar un paseo",
        "answer": "I went for a walk" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "OTHER",
        "question": "Ellos no se llevan muy bien",
        "answer": "They aren't getting on very well" 
    },
    {
        "group_id": "OTHER",
        "question": "Estaba escuchando música cuando alguien llamó a la puerta",
        "answer": "I was listen to music when somebody knocked on the door" 
    }
]